# FLORENCE MBABAZI

Kigali, Rwanda | +250782592552 | mbabaziflorence07@gmail.com | https://github.com/mbabazif www.linkedin.com/in/florence-mbabazi

### **Personal Statements**

As a Data Analyst I have a strong passion for developing Dashboards, Reports, Data Models, and performance-related insights. Since I can map the Business Requirements as a Business Analytics and as a Data Analyst then translate them into operational dashboards and performance-related insights, I can always develop a solution without any miscommunication with stakeholders. Automating the processes concerning Data Extraction and Data Transformation also falls under my expertise.

### **Skills**

Data Analyst

- Advanced Excel
- PowerBI
- SQL
- Python
- Machine Learning

Web Develoment

- Python(Django)
- HTMI
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- Postgres & Mysql

Personal Skills

- Continuous Learning
- Work underpressure
- Team Work
- Quick Learner
- Accuracy and attention to details

## **Academic Qualification**

### AzubiAfrica(Acra, Ghana)

September 2022 - 2024

Business Analytics & Data Analytics

Award: Certificates

### Skills:

- Explore Important Formulas and Functions in MS Excel
- Create Charts and Visualisations using MS Excel
- Load datasets and establish table relationships in PowerBI
- Build different type of charts and dashboards in PowerBI
- Work with Map visualisations and other advanced charts with drill down functionalities in PowerBI
- Work with power query for data manipulation in PowerBI
- Write DAX expressions in PowerBI
- Familiar with MySQL, Create & update reports in SQL
- Perform Data Analysis using SQL
- Explore Python for Data Exploration and Statistical Inference
- Use Matplotlib and Seaborn for data visualisation
- Create charts to visualise data and generate insights
- Univariate, Bivariate and Multivariate analysis using python
- Perform Statistical Analysis on real world datasets
- Build and Validate Hypothesis using statistical tests
- Generate useful insights from the data

### Moringa School November 2018 - May 2019

Web Development Award: Certificate

### Skills

Python(Django), HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and Postgres

#### Inilak

May 2012 - December 2016

Bachelor Of Science in Information Systems and Management

Award: Bachelor's Degree

#### Skills:

Networking, Information Security, Web Programing, Management, Finance, Accounting, Cost Accounting and Principle of Economics

### **Employment History**

MobiCash LTD, Web Development, Kigali October 2019 - Currently Responsibilities:

- Integrating data from various back-end services and databases.
- Gathering and refining specifications and requirements based on technical needs.
- Creating and maintaining software documentation.
- Designing website layout and user interface using standard HTML, CSS, and JavaScript practices, along with the Django framework, Python, and other relevant tools.
- Maintaining, expanding, and scaling websites and web applications.
- Being responsible for the coding, design, and layout of a website according to the company's specifications.
- Writing and designing testable, efficient code using best software development practices.
- Familiarity with Operating Systems (Linux and Windows).

### IT support officer Intern, Rwanda Education

Board, March 2017 - 2017

### Responsibilities:

- Generating reports for each school to assist One Laptop Per Child in assessing the completion of the work.
- Installing and configuring computer hardware, operating systems, and required applications.
- As a help desk technician, I accomplish my tasks by listening to end users and acting on their feedback.
- Troubleshooting system and network problems, such as checking the wireless adapter, WAN and LAN connections, and verifying the wireless access point and network.
- Installing the Prodigy program on XO laptops to enable teachers and students to access content on the server using XO laptops.
- Maintaining the XO laptops and installing the key, as it expires after one year.
- Creating reports for each school to assist One Laptop Per Child in assessing the progress of the work.

### **Projects**

### **Indian StartUp Funding Ecosystem**

• Indian startup ecosystem The analysis aims to uncover trends, patterns, and key factors that contribute to the success of startups in India. LinkedinArticleLink:https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/indian-startup-funding-ecosystem-in-depth-analysis-from-mbabazi

### **Customer Churn Analysis and Prediction**

customer churn or turnover we aim to predict customer churn and understand the key indicators of churn by analyzing a dataset containing various customer attributes

LinkeinArticleLink: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/customer-churn-analysis-prediction-florence-mbabazi">https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/customer-churn-analysis-prediction-florence-mbabazi</a>

### **Corporation Favorita Sales Prediction**

 Corporation Favorita, a large Ecuadorian-based grocery retailer. This project involves predicting future sales for a grocery retailer based on historical sales data and other relevant information.
LinkedinArticleLink: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/store-sales-time-series-forecasting-florence-mbabazi">https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/store-sales-time-series-forecasting-florence-mbabazi</a>

### Sepsis Analysis(FastAPI)

• This project focuses on early sepsis detection and classification, a critical aspect of healthcare. Timely identification of sepsis significantly enhances patient outcomes.

LinkeinArticle: https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/sepsis-classification-machine-learning-project-florence-mbabazi-fn5if

### References

Jackeline Kayitesi System Administrator ISCO Rwanda Ltd Tel: +250788312907

Email: kavitesijacqueline@gmail.com

Patrick Ngabonziza Chairman Mobicash Ltd Phone: +250788603800

Email: ngabo@mobicashonline.com

Tuyisenge Marie Claire Technical Support Engineer Tek Experts Phone: +250784357668

Email: tblaguese1@gmail.com